<?xml version="1.0"?>

<PropertyList>

	<nasal>
	  

		<load>
			<![CDATA[
			print("Loading MiG-21bis bombable", cmdarg().getPath());

      var nodeName = cmdarg().getPath(); 

      ##checks whether it has been initialized already; if so, just return
      if ( bombable.check_overall_initialized (nodeName) ) return;

			
			

############################################
#MiG-21bis INITIALIZER
			var object_init = func() {
				# Datas of this object are under: cmdarg().getPath()
				var thisNodeName = cmdarg().getPath();
				var thisNode = props.globals.getNode(thisNodeName);
				# Add some useful nodes


				
        ########################################################################
        ########################################################################
        # INITIALIZE BOMBABLE
        # 
        # Initialize constants and main routines for maintaining altitude
        # relative to ground-level, relocating after file/reset, and 
        # creating bombable/shootable objects.
        # 
        # These routines are found in FG/nasal/bombable.nas
        #  
        ########################################################################               
        # INITIALIZE BOMBABLE Object
        # This object will be slurped in the object's node as a child
        # node named "bombable".                 
        # All distances are specified in meters.
        # All altitudes are relative to current ground level at the object's 
        # location
        # 
         
        thisNodeName = cmdarg().getPath(); 

        var bombableObject = {  
          
          
          objectNodeName : thisNodeName,
          objectNode : props.globals.getNode(thisNodeName),
          updateTime_s : 1/3, #time, in seconds, between the updates that 
          #keep the object at its AGL. Tradeoff is high-speed updates look more
          #realistic but slow down the framerate/cause jerkiness.  Faster-moving
          #objects will need more frequent updates to look realistic.
          #update time faster than about 1/3 seems to have a noticeable effect
          #on frame rate                    

		                        
          #########################################                              
          # ALTITUDE DEFINITIONS
          #         
          altitudes : {	
            wheelsOnGroundAGL_m : 1 , #altitude correction to add to your aircraft or ship that is needed to put wheels on ground (or, for a ship, make it float in the water at the correct level).  For most objects this is 0 but some models need a small correction to place them exactly at ground level
            
            minimumAGL_m : 50, #minimum altitude above ground level this object is allowed to fly
            maximumAGL_m : 19000, #maximum altitude AGL this object is allowed to fly, ie, operational ceiling	    
            crashedAGL_m : 0.6, #altitude AGL when crashed.  Ships will sink to this level, aircraft or vehicles will sink into the ground as landing gear collapses or tires deflate. Should be negative, even just -0.001.
          },
          #  
          #########################################
          # VELOCITIES DEFINITIONS
          # 
          velocities : {               
            maxSpeedReduce_percent : 0.5, #max % to reduce speed, per step, when damaged
            minSpeed_kt : 170, #minimum speed to reduce to when damaged.  Ground vehicles and ships might stop completely when damaged but aircraft will need a minimum speed so they keep moving until they hit the ground.
            cruiseSpeed_kt : 500, #cruising speed, typical/optimal cruising speed, V C for aircraft
            
            attackSpeed_kt : 550, #typical/optimal speed when aggressively attacking or evading, in
                                 #level flight for aircraft
            
            maxSpeed_kt : 1356 , #Maximum possible speed under dive or downhill conditions, V NE for aircraft
    
            damagedAltitudeChangeMaxRate_meterspersecond : 300, #max rate to sink or fly downwards when damaged, in meters/second
            
            #The terminal velocities are calculated by opening the 'real' AC 
            #in FG, level flight, full throttle, then putting
            #the AC at different angles of attack with the autopilot,
            #and noting the terminal airspeed & vertical speed velocities.
            #For best results, do it near sea level, under 5000 feet altitude.
            #One or two each of climb & dive velocities are probably sufficient.
            #However if you do more we may be able to use the more precise
            #data in the future.
            #
            #Note that these are intended to be true airspeed whereas FG's
            #/velocities/airspeed-kt reports indicated airspeed, so some 
            #conversion or reference to groundspeed-kt is needed.
            # 
            #In FG /velocities/groundspeed-kt is equal (or close 
            #to equal, except for wind . . .) true airspeed when pitch=0 
            #but as pitch increases or decreases that will change.
            #  
                                    
            diveTerminalVelocities: {
                point1: { airspeed_kt : 447.6, vertical_speed_fps : - 74.4},
                point2: { airspeed_kt : 498.4, vertical_speed_fps : - 167.1},
                point3: { airspeed_kt : 535, vertical_speed_fps : - 255.0},
                point4: { airspeed_kt : 556, vertical_speed_fps : - 343.9},
                
                
                
            },

            climbTerminalVelocities: {
              point1: { airspeed_kt : 331.2, vertical_speed_fps : 34.3},
              point2: { airspeed_kt : 266.7, vertical_speed_fps : 59.4},
              point3: { airspeed_kt : 169.7, vertical_speed_fps : 73.1},
               
            },

            
          },
          #  
          #########################################
          # EVASION DEFINITIONS
          # 
          # The evasion system makes the AI aircraft dodge when they come under
          # fire. 
          evasions : {               
            dodgeDelayMax_sec : 15, #max time to delay/wait between dodges
            dodgeDelayMin_sec : 5, #minimum time to delay/wait between dodges
            dodgeMax_deg : 75, #Max amount to turn when dodging
                              #90 degrees = instant turn, unrealistic
                              #up to 80 is usually OK, somewhere in 80-85 starts to be unrealistically fast
                              #>85 is usually very unrealistic.  You must test this in your scenario, however.
            
            dodgeMin_deg : 57, #minimum amount to turn when dodging
            rollRateMax_degpersec : 110, #you can figure this out by rolling the corresponding FG aircraft and timing a 180 or 360 deg roll                                                      
            dodgeROverLPreference_percent : 50, # Preference for right turns vs. left when dodging.  90% means 90% right turns, 50% means 50% right turns.
            dodgeAltMin_m : -5000, #Aircraft will begin to move up or down 
            dodgeAltMax_m : 5000, #Max & Min are relative to current alt 
            dodgeVertSpeedClimb_mps : 100, #Max speed to climb when evading
            dodgeVertSpeedDive_mps : 200, #Max speed to dive when evading 
          },
          #  
          #########################################
          # ATTACK DEFINITIONS
          # 
          # The attack system makes the AI aircraft turn and fly towards 
          # other aircraft 
          attacks : {               
            maxDistance_m : 14000, #max distance to turn & attack main aircraft
            minDistance_m : 2500, #min distance to turn & attack main aircraft, ie, fly away this far before turning to attack again
            continueAttackAngle_deg : 20, #when within minDistance_m, the aircraft will continue to turn towards the main aircraft and attack *if* if the angle is less than this amount from dead ahead
            altitudeHigherCutoff_m : 13000, # will attack the main aircraft unless this amount higher than it or more
            altitudeLowerCutoff_m : 5000, # will attack the main aircraft unless this amount lower than it or more
            climbPower : 6000, # How powerful the aircraft is when climbing during an attack; 4000 would be typical for, say a Zero--scale accordingly for others; higher is stronger
            divePower : 9000, # How powerful the aircraft is when diving during and attack; 6000 typical of a Zero--could be much more than climbPower if the aircraft is a weak climber but a strong diver              
            rollMin_deg : 58, #when turning on attack, roll to this angle min
            rollMax_deg : 75, #when turning on attack, roll to this angle max
                              #90 degrees = instant turn, unrealistic
                              #up to 80 might be OK, depending on aircraft & speed; somewhere in 80-85 starts to be unrealistically fast
                              #>85 is usually very unrealistic.  You must test this in your scenario, however.
            rollRateMax_degpersec : 110, #you can figure this out by rolling the corresponding FG aircraft and timing a 180 or 360 deg roll                                                                  
            attackCheckTime_sec : 10, # check for need to attack/correct course this often  
            attackCheckTimeEngaged_sec : 0.7, # once engaged with enemy, check/update course this frequently
                
          },
          
          #  
          #########################################
          # WEAPONS DEFINITIONS
          # 
          # The weapons system makes the AI aircraft fire on the main aircraft 
          # You can define any number of weapons--just enclose each in curly brackets
          # and separate with commas (,).           
          weapons : {
             front_gun :  #internal name - this can be any name you want; must be a valid nasal variable name
              {               
                name : "GSh-23", # name presented to users, ie in on-screen messages
                maxDamage_percent : 30, # maximum percentage damage one hit from the aircraft's main weapon/machine guns will do to an opponent
                maxDamageDistance_m : 700, # maximum distance at which the aircrafts main weapon/maching guns will be able to damage an opponent
                weaponAngle_deg  :  { heading: 0, elevation: 0 }, # direction the aircraft's main weapon is aimed.   
                                                                  # 0,0 = straight ahead, 90,0=directly right, 0,90=directly up, 0,180=directly back, etc.
                weaponOffset_m : {x:2.5, y:0, z:0}, # Offset of the weapon from the main aircraft center
                weaponSize_m : {start:.23, end:.23}, # Visual size of the weapon's projectile, in meters, at start & end of its path

              },    
          },  
          
          #  
          #########################################
          # DIMENSION DEFINITIONS
          #           
          dimensions : {                  
            width_m : 7.15,  #width of your object, ie, for aircraft, wingspan
            length_m : 15.76, #length of your object, ie, for aircraft, distance nose to tail
            height_m : 4.10, #height of your object, ie, for aircraft ground to highest point when sitting on runway
            
            damageRadius_m : 8, #typically 1/2 the longest dimension of the object. Hits within this distance of the 
                                #center of object have some possibility of damage
            vitalDamageRadius_m : 2, #typically the radius of the fuselage or cockpit or other most 
                                     # vital area at the center of the object.  Always smaller than damageRadius_m
                                    
            crashRadius_m : 6, #It's a crash if the main aircraft hits in this area.
                                
          },
          #
          #########################################
          # VULNERABILITIES DEFINITIONS        
          #
          vulnerabilities : {                   
            damageVulnerability : 8, #Vulnerability to damage from armament, 1=normal M1 tank; higher to make objects easier to kill and lower to make them more difficult.  This is a multiplier, so 5 means 5X easier to kill than an M1, 1/5 means 5X harder to kill. 
            
            engineDamageVulnerability_percent : 8, #Chance that a small-caliber machine-gun round will damage the engine.       
            
            fireVulnerability_percent : 7, #Vulnerability to catching on fire. 100% means even the slightest impact will set it on fire; 20% means quite difficult to set on fire; 0% means set on fire only when completely damaged; -1% means never set on fire.                          
            
            fireDamageRate_percentpersecond : .5, #Amount of damage to add, per second, when on fire.  100%=completely damaged. Warthog is relatively damage-resistant.
            
            fireExtinguishMaxTime_seconds : 80, #Once a fire starts, for this many seconds there is a chance to put out the fire; fires lasting longer than this won't be put out until the object burns out.
            
            fireExtinguishSuccess_percentage : 50, #Chance of the crew putting out the fire within the MaxTime above. Warthoge is relatively damage-resistant.
            
            explosiveMass_kg : 15000 , #mass of the object in KG, but give at least a 2-10X bonus to anything carrying flammables or high explosives.
          },
          #
          #########################################
          # LIVERY DEFINITIONS
          #
          # Path to livery files to use at different damage levels.
          # Path is relative to the AI aircraft's directory.
          # The object will start with the first livery listed and 
          # change to succeeding liveries as the damage
          # level increases. The final livery should indicate full damage/
          # object destroyed.        
          # 
          # If you don't want to specify any special liveries simply set 
          # damageLivery : nil and the object's normal livery will be used.  
          #                                                            
          damageLiveries : {
            damageLivery : [  ]                        
          },
                            
        };

        #########################################
        # INITIALIZE ROUTINES
        # 
        # OVERALL INITIALIZER: Needed to make all the others work
        bombable.initialize ( bombableObject );
        #
        # LOCATION: Relocate object to maintain its position after file/reset       
        # (best not used for airplanes)
        # bombable.location_init ( thisNodeName );
        #
        # GROUND: Keep object at altitude relative to ground level
        bombable.ground_init ( thisNodeName );
        #
        # ATTACK: Make the object attack the main aircraft        
        bombable.attack_init ( thisNodeName );
        #
        # WEAPONS: Make the object shoot the main aircraft        
        bombable.weapons_init ( thisNodeName );                
        #
        # BOMBABLE: Make the object bombable/damageable        
        bombable.bombable_init ( thisNodeName );
        #
        # SMOKE/CONTRAIL: Start a flare, contrail, smoke trail, or exhaust 
        # trail for the object.
        # Smoke types available: flare, jetcontrail, pistonexhaust, smoketrail,
        # damagedengine                        
        # bombable.startSmoke("jetcontrail", thisNodeName );
        #
        # END INITIALIZE BOMBABLE
        ########################################################################
        ########################################################################                
	      

				
			}
			
			object_init();
			]]>
		</load>
		<unload>
			<![CDATA[
			print("Unload MiG-21bis.");
      var nodeName= cmdarg().getPath();  
      bombable.de_overall_initialize( nodeName );
      bombable.initialize_del( nodeName );
      bombable.ground_del( nodeName );
      bombable.location_del (nodeName);
      bombable.bombable_del( nodeName );
      bombable.attack_del( nodeName );
      bombable.weapons_del (nodeName);      
#  </unload>

			]]>
		</unload>
 </nasal>  

</PropertyList>
